Hello and welcome to my Internet History course. My name is Charles Severance and I'm a faculty
member at the University of Michigan School of Information. I've been working on this
material for nearly 30 years. For me, it goes back to the mid-1990s, just when the Internet
was getting started. At that time, I had a wonderful chance to work with some friends
to produce a television show about the Internet. We didn't know what it would become, so we
went around filming people, capturing ideas, and collecting what turned out to be a nice
informal history of the early Internet. Around that same time, I was also experimenting with
teaching using the Internet. In fact, I was one of the first professors in the world to
stream a four-credit semester-long class entirely online. It was so early I couldn't even stream
video the first semester, just audio, slides, and a scary picture of me in the upper left
hand corner. Over the years, I kept collecting stories and building teaching tools and interviewing
people that helped create the Internet. And all that came together in the original version
of this course in 2013. This latest version is updated and refined. The idea behind this
course is simple. You can't really understand technology without understanding its history.
Technology evolves over time, shaped by people, constraints, opportunities, and decisions
that don't always seem important at the moment. This course grew out of a Python class I also
taught for many years in the mid-2000s. Right after a difficult midterm exam, I would give
the students a break from programming and step back and give their learning a larger
context. So that's the history. That's the backstory. Now let's get started. And we'll
begin with what I think of as the beginning. Codebreaking at Bletchley Park, in the 1940s,
just north of London, England.